Guide to the Leverett S. Ropes Papers 1888-1952
Montana Historical Society
Leverett S. Ropes papers
1888-1952
Montana Historical Society Archives
MC 196
Ropes, Leverett S. (Leverett Smith), 1868-1953
5.5 linear feet of shelf space.
Helena, Montana, mining and geological engineer Leverett Ropes (1868-1953) was employed by various mining firms, by the federal government, and as a private consultant. This collection contains papers (ca. 1888-1952) concerning Ropes' mining engineering and geology consulting work and his interest in a variety of political issues. The general correspondence (1928-1952) concerns mines in Lewis and Clark, Jefferson, and Broadwater counties, Fort Peck Dam, his dispute with federal agencies over financing of Montana mining ventures, and issues of personal interest to Ropes such as the repeal of prohibition and New Deal policies. In addition there is biographical material (1935-1946); court papers (1910, 1940); financial records (1936-1951); legal documents (1928-1943) for several mining companies; reports (1929-1952) by Ropes and others on numerous mining properties; speeches and writings (1929-1952) on mining and politics, including the lawlessness (racketeering) caused by prohibition; miscellany (1891-1947); and clippings.
Biographical Note:
Leverett S. Ropes was born in Ishpeming, Michigan, on July 21, 1868, the son of Julius and Eunice Rouse Ropes. Julius Ropes was a drug store owner and chemist, who did analytical work for many of the Ishpeming region's mines. He was also the developer of the Ropes Mine, a gold property. Leverett Ropes studied mining geology under his father's tutelage and then attended Michigan College of Mining and Technology, graduating in 1893.
Leverett Ropes' early professional work was in the field of corundum mining and milling. He spent several years in North Carolina and Georgia and a year in Comberemere, Ontario, working with corundum. Using this experience he secured employment with the Montana Corundum Company to develop their mine near Gallatin Gateway. However, his real goal was to move to Montana to get into the quartz mining industry. During the next few years he worked for a number of different mining companies in Montana including the Montana Coal and Coke Company at Gardiner, the Jardine Mining Company at Jardine, the Bald Butte Gold Mining Company at Marysville, the Bullion Mine at Basin, and the Alta Mine at Wickes. In addition to his mining work Ropes worked on the construction of Mystic, Lake Dam near Bozeman and Hauser Dam near Helena. He also served briefly as a mineral inspector for the U.S. General Land Office from 1908 to 1910, and for the U.S. Forest Service in the fall of 1930.
In 1910 Ropes began doing private consulting work in partnership with Robert McIntyre. He incorporated under the name Intermountain Engineering-Development Company in 1919 to seek outside capital to finance Montana mining ventures. In July 1928 Ropes lost all of his mining records, reports, correspondence, survey notes, etc. in the fire which destroyed the Bailey Block and several other buildings in downtown Helena. Since his ability to interest investors in Montana mining properties was based on his extensive knowledge of these properties, the loss of his records crippled his work. During the 1930s and 194Os he gradually rebuilt his files, based partly on memory and partly on re-examination of many properties.
Leverett S. Ropes married Eleanor Husk Deal of Franklin, North Carolina, on December 12, 1894. The couple had four children: Dorothy, John, Judith, and Leverett. Leverett S. Ropes died on May 27, 1953.
This collection contains papers of Leverett S. Ropes concerning his mining engineering and geology consulting work and relative to his interest in political issues. The general correspondence (1928-1952) mostly concerns mines in Lewis and Clark, Jefferson, and Broadwater counties, but also includes files on the Fort Peck Dam, on Ropes' disputes with federal agencies over financing of Montana mining ventures, and on New Deal polities. It also includes letters to and from members of his family, potential mine investors, political figures, government agencies, newspapers, and others about a wide variety of subjects. In addition there are biographical information (1935-1946); court papers (1910, 1940); financial records (1936-1951); legal documents (1928-1943) for several mining companies; reports (1896-1938) by Ropes and others on numerous mining properties; speeches and writings (1929-1952) on mining and politics; miscellany (1891-1947); and clippings (1928-1949).
Arranged by series. Some material housed in Archives Map Case, Oversize Box, and Archives Rolled Maps. See inventory below for more information.
Collection open for research.
Acquisition information available upon request
Printed material, most maps, photographs, and artifacts have been transferred to the Library, Library Map Collection, Photograph Archives, and Museum respectively. See inventory below for more information.
This collection is indexed under the following headings in the Montana Historical Society Archives catalog. Researchers desiring materials about related topics, persons, or places should search under these terms.
Ropes, Leverett S. (Leverett Smith), 1868-1953
Dams--Montana.; Earthquakes--Montana--Helena; Geologists--Montana; Geology--Montana; Gold mines and mining--Montana; Corundum mines and mining--Montana; Lead mines and mining--Montana; Manganese mines and mining--Montana; Mines and mineral resources--Idaho; Mines and mineral resources--Michigan; Mines and mineral resources--Montana--Beaverhead County; Mines and mineral resources--Montana--Broadwater County; Mines and mineral resources--Montana--Cascade County; Mines and mineral resources--Montana--Fergus County; Mines and mineral resources--Montana--Gallatin County; Mines and mineral resources--Montana--Jefferson County; Mines and mineral resources--Montana--Judith Basin County; Mines and mineral resources--Montana--Lewis and Clark County; Mines and mineral resources--Montana--Madison County; Mines and mineral resources--Montana--Missoula County; Mines and mineral resources--Montana--Park County; Mines and mineral resources--Montana--Powell County; Mines and mineral resources--South Dakota; Mining engineering--Montana; Mining machinery--Design and construction; Prohibition; Silver mines and mining--Montana; Strikes and lockouts--Montana; Talc industry--Montana; Uranium mines and mining--Montana; Mining claims--Montana; Mine brokers--Montana
Beaverhead County (Mont.); Broadwater County (Mont.); Carbonate Mine (Lewis and Clark County, Mont.); Dobler Mine (Clasoil, Mont.); Drumlummon Mine (Marysville, Mont.); Elk Creek Corundum Mine (Gallatin Gateway, Mont.); Elkhorn (Mont.); Fergus County (Mont.); Fort Peck Dam (Mont.); Free Enterprise Uranium-Radon Mine (Boulder, Mont.); Gold Bug Mine (Yogo Gulch, Mont.); Golden Curry Mine (Elkhorn, Mont.); Helena (Mont.)--Earthquake, 1935; Helena (Mont.); Jefferson County (Mont.); Judith Basin County (Mont.); Lewis and Clark County (Mont.); Lolo National Forest (Mont.); Madison County (Mont.); Marietta Mine (Townsend, Mont.); Marysville (Mont.); Mike Horse Mine (Mont.); Missoula County (Mont.); Mount Belmont Gold Mines (Marysville, Mont.); Park County (Mont.); Penobscot Mine (Marysville, Mont.); Powell County (Mont.); Reinig Placer Mine (Lewis and Clark County, Mont.); Towsley Mines (Marysville, Mont.); Victory Mine (Ophir Gulch, Mont.); Wickes (Mont.); Empire Mine (Marysville, Mont.)
Montana
Mines and Mineral Resources
Detailed Description of the Collection
The following section contains a detailed listing of the materials in the collection
- Biographical Materials
  - Resumes and other autobiographical writings, 1935-1946, undated (Box-folder 1 / 1)
- General Correspondence
  - Air mail contract system, 1934 (Box-folder 1 / 2)
  - Alhambra Gold Mines, Inc., Jefferson County (re Fleming, Pilot, Katie, Golden Gate mines, Warm Springs Creek; correspondents include Mike Sullivan, James R. Brophy, J.W. Goldsbury, C.R. Bralzier, Harfield Conrad, Gerald Conrad), 1929-1934, 1939-1946 (Box-folder 1 / 3)
  - Alta Corbin Mines Co., Wickes (Ann Randall), 1932 (Box-folder 1 / 4)
  - Alta Mine, Wickes (correspondents include R.T. Walker, C.V. Brennan, Paul E. Flynn, Isle Royal Copper Co., Blair W. Stewart, Harvey Mudd, L.W. Wickes), 1928-1950 (Box-folder 1 / 5)
  - Alta Mine, Wickes (re dumps; correspondents include E.R. Willis, E.W. Hyde, Frank Book), 1947-1949 (Box-folder 1 / 6)
  - Alta Mine, Wickes (re equipment, etc.), 1947-1948 (Box-folder 1 / 7)
  - Alta Mines Corporation, New York, Wickes (correspondents include Clyde Weed, L.E. Whicher, Ted Thorbergson, Floyd O. Small), 1938-1952 (Box-folder 1 / 8-10)
  - Alta Mines Inc., Portland, Oregon, Wickes (correspondents include E.W. Hyde, Helen Hyde, E.B. MacNaughton, H.B. Christopher, George S. Reid, Alfred G. Rouse, W.N. Brown, Maurice Hudson), 1946-1950 (Box-folder 1 / 11-13)
  - Alta Ruby and K. and H. Mining, Wickes (correspondents include Mrs. A.E. Raines; includes claim lease), 1946-1950 (Box-folder 1 / 14)
  - American Flag Mine, Holmes Gulch, Jefferson County (Frank F. Raitt), 1934 (Box-folder 1 / 15)
  - A, 1930-1951 (Box-folder 1 / 16)
  - G.A. Bailey (re gold prospects in Montana), 1934-1935 (Box-folder 1 / 17)
  - Bald Butte Mining and Milling Company, Marysville (William M. Belcher), 1930, 1933 (Box-folder 1 / 18)
  - Baltimore Mine, Boulder (Louis P. Donovan), 1935 (Box-folder 2 / 1)
  - Barite (correspondents include Amos Roberts, A.H. Raymond, R.C. Tarrant, Montana Oil Journal), 1946 (Box-folder 2 / 2)
  - Bell Boy Gold Mining Company, Marysville (re Bell Boy and Towsley mines; correspondents include Mike Savage, W.H. Abel), 1932-1942 (Box-folder 2 / 3)
  - Francis A. Bell (re Ropes family legal matters), 1942-1943 (Box-folder 2 / 4)
  - Belmont Mines, Inc., Marysville (re Thomas Cruse Mining and Development Company, Mt. Belmont Gold Mines, Bald Butte Mines, etc.; correspondents include Marry Hickey, Clement Quinn, J. Cleveland Haas, Joseph Hyman, James R. Thomas, George Arnott, Roy C. Tarrant), 1925-1941 (Box-folder 2 / 5-7)
  - Belt Mountain Lead Mining Company (re Silver and Bell Mine, Barker Mining District; correspondents include R.W. Wilson, Lars Carlson), 1931-1932, 1937 (Box-folder 2 / 8)
  - Big Blackfoot Gold Mine, Lincoln (J.A. Rowand, W.S. Norman), 1931-1932, 1936 (Box-folder 2 / 9)
  - Big Chief Mine, Broadwater County (W.L. Barrett, Herschel James, A.F. Mavity), 1930-1937 (Box-folder 2 / 10)
  - Birds Eye Claim, Elkhorn (re Heagan claim; correspondents include Lillian McKereghan), 1932-1933 (Box-folder 2 / 11)
  - Blackjack Mine, Corbin (Edith Dunn Keith), 1934 (Box-folder 2 / 12)
  - Blizzard Mine, Wickes (J.L. Penner, J.P. Hiebert), 1936, 1938-1939 (Box-folder 2 / 13)
  - Blue Bird Mine, Wolf Creek (Karl Herter), 1929 (Box-folder 2 / 14)
  - Blue Cloud Placer Mine, Helena (re tungsten and scheelite; correspondents include Blanche Keller, S.M. Anderson), 1930, 1940-1943 (Box-folder 2 / 15)
  - "Blueprint" (re misuse of word), 1943 (Box-folder 2 / 16)
  - Boulder Belle Mining Company, Elkhorn (re C & D and Louise mines; correspondents include John C. Sloss, C.A. Clarke, Dutton Clarke), 1909, 1932-1949 (Box-folder 2 / 17-19)
  - James F. Brophy and James R. Brophy (re Bald Butte, Penobscot, Dobler and other mines), 1933-1937, 1942 (Box-folder 2 / 20)
  - B, 1929-1947 (Box-folder 2 / 21)
  - Canada Dept. of Mines and Resources (re Canadian corundum mine), 1945 (Box-folder 2 / 22)
  - Canyon Ferry Dam (John L. Savage), 1946, 1949 (Box-folder 2 / 23)
  - Capital Consolidated Mining Company, Holmes Gulch, Jefferson County (correspondents include Weston Clarke, Dutton Clarke, L.B. Sandblast; also includes draft of application to Reconstruction Finance Corp.), 1932,, 1934, 1942-1948 (Box-folder 3 / 1)
  - Capital Oil Well, Winston (H.C. Barth), 1930 (Box-folder 3 / 2)
  - Carbonate Mine, Silver Camp (correspondents include J.A. Rowand, Blackfoot Silver Lead Mining Company, C.L. Holmberg, Tonopah Mining Company, Hunter Williams, Clement K. Quinn), 1926-1932, 1937 (Box-folder 3 / 3)
  - Channel Gold Mines, Ltd. (re Channel Gold Mines, Bald Butte; correspondents include Belle Channel, H.R. Pettijohn, Like Chapman, S.H. Fairweather, J.F. Dyche), 1932-1941 (Box-folder 3 / 4)
  - Coal (correspondents include Samuel Ford, Montana Record Herald), 1942, 1948 (Box-folder 3 / 5)
  - E.E. Collins (re legal matters), 1942-1943 (Box-folder 3 / 6)
  - Co-op Gold Mine, Helena (correspondents include Educational Cooperative Publishing Company, J.B. Bentley), 1939 (Box-folder 3 / 7)
  - Charles Cummings (re talc, marble, Michigan mines), 1930-1935 (Box-folder 3 / 8)
  - Custer Mine, Winston (Walter Harvey Weed, Albert C. Fisher), 1932 (Box-folder 3 / 9)
  - C, 1928-1951 (Box-folder 3 / 10)
  - Davis Placer, Townsend (Frank O. Davis), 1932-1934 (Box-folder 3 / 11)
  - S.R. Davis (re Little Goldie, Western Hope, and Shield's Last Stand mines, Boulder), 1945 (Box-folder 3 / 12)
  - Dobler Mine, Clasoil (correspondents include Rudolph Dobler, Martin Naddy, W.L. Honnold, Louis P. Donovan, H.B. Chessher, Harry Tilton), 1931-1938 (Box-folder 3 / 13)
  - Drumlummon Extension Mine, Marysville (correspondents include Edward J. Dailey, Scott Calhoun, Associated Gold Mines Company), 1932-1935 (Box-folder 3 / 14)
  - Dunlap claims, Magpie Gulch, Broadwater County (H.W. Turner), 1934 (Box-folder 3 / 15)
  - D, 1929-1948 (Box-folder 3 / 16)
  - East Pacific Mine, Winston (correspondents include R.M. Anderson, H.W. Carver, U.S. War Production Board), 1937, 1942-1943 (Box-folder 3 / 17)
  - Elk Creek corundum mine, Gallatin County (correspondents include Edmund G. Toomey, Engineering and Mining Journal, U.S. War Production Board, Reconstruction Finance Corp., American Abrasive Company, U.S. Public Roads Administration), 1907, 1932, 1942-1943 (Box-folder 3 / 18)
  - Elk Creek corundum mine, Gallatin County (correspondents include U.S. War Production Board, Reconstruction Finance Corp., Federal Loan Agency, Metals Reserve Company, American Abrasive Company, Bausch and Lomb Optical Company, Flying D. Ranges, Inc., U.S. Bureau of Mines, George Sinton, Defense Minerals Administration; also includes Bureau of Mines reports annotated by Ropes), 1944-1951 (Box-folder 4 / 1-4)
  - Engineering and Mining Journal (re article, letters to the editor, etc.), 1929-1950 (Box-folder 4 / 5)
  - John E. Erickson (re appointment to U.S. Senate), 1933 (Box-folder 4 / 6)
  - Eureka Mining Company, Marysville (correspondents include Lide Chapman, charles Gibbons), 1938-1939 (Box-folder 4 / 7)
  - E, 1932-1950 (Box-folder 4 / 8)
  - Fleming Mine, Alhambra (correspondents include James F. Brophy, Newbourgh Mining and Milling Company), 1933, 1937 (Box-folder 4 / 9)
  - Fort Peck Dam, 1934-1939 (Box-folder 4 / 10)
  - Fort Peck Dam hydroelectric project and World War II, 1942 (Box-folder 4 / 11)
  - Frankenfield claims, Dry Gulch, Helena (correspondents include Cecil Murphy, W.A. Smith), 1932 (Box-folder 4 / 12)
  - Freedom of press (re corporate control of Montana press and U.S. Post Office complicity), 1933-1934 (Box-folder 4 / 13)
  - F, 1931-1948 (Box-folder 4 / 14)
  - Geology of Helena Valley (U.S. Public Works Administration), 1936 (Box-folder 4 / 15)
  - Gibson and Lambert Associates (re Who's Who in Engineering account), 1933-1934 (Box-folder 4 / 16)
  - Gold (re gold standard, gold miners' code under National Recovery Act, etc.), 1933-1934, 1937, 1949 (Box-folder 4 / 17)
  - Gold Bug Mine [Weatherwax Mine], Yogo (Walter C. Lehman), 1944-1947 (Box-folder 4 / 18)
  - Gold Canyon Mining Company (re Gold Canyon Group, Channel Gold Mine, and Granite Butte mines, Gould; correspondents include Belle Channel, Fred J. Anderson), 1929-1931 (Box-folder 4 / 19)
  - Gold King Mining Company, Winston (correspondents include E.J. McCabe, Charles P. Day), 1937-1939 (Box-folder 4 / 20)
  - Gold Strike Mining Company, Hassel (re Morning Glory Mine), 1932 (Box-folder 5 / 1)
  - Golden Crown Mine, Scratchgravel Mining District (correspondents include R.M. Elder Walter L. Morgan, John Howard, Patented Mines Company, Ed Jennings), 1934-1940 (Box-folder 5 / 2)
  - Golden Curry Mine, Elkhorn (correspondents include A.A. Pelletier, E.E. Esselstyn, H.B. Chessher, A.C. Johnson, Lillian McKereghan, C.L. Holmberg, Ford Johnson; also includes copy of 1912 report on mine), 1930-1934 (Box-folder 5 / 3)
  - Golden Jack Mine, Fergus County (correspondents include E.W. Carmichael, F.V.H. Collins, J.M. Bair, J.T. Skinner; includes prospectus and assays for mines), 1929-1931 (Box-folder 5 / 4)
  - Great Eastern and Great Western claims, Emigrant (K.L. Kearns), 1940 (Box-folder 5 / 5)
  - Louis Green's mine, Townsend, 1942-1944 (Box-folder 5 / 6)
  - G, 1930-1947 (Box-folder 5 / 7)
  - H & A Manufacturing Company (re "serpentine" heating unit), 1945 (Box-folder 5 / 8)
  - Hall Mining Company, Rimini (re Peerless Jennie and Crescent mines; correspondents include W.A. Hall, M.O. Wilkins), 1949 (Box-folder 5 / 9)
  - John D.M. Hamilton (re Republican National Committee), 1936-1937 (Box-folder 5 / 10)
  - E.G. Harris (re Silver Bell, Smith and Harris, Prince Group, and Florence mines, Maiden), 1934-1938 (Box-folder 5 / 11)
  - Frank A. Hazelbaker (re campaign for Governor), 1932 (Box-folder 5 / 12)
  - Helena-Jefferson Mines Company (correspondents include P.H. Whiting, Timber Butte Milling Company, Charles Hussey, R.T. Walker, W.G. Smart, Northwest Mines Investment Company, W.J. Croze), 1926-1930, 1942 (Box-folder 5 / 13)
  - Helena schools, 1929, 1932, 1936-1938 (Box-folder 5 / 14)
  - Helena street system, 1941-1943, 1950 (Box-folder 5 / 15)
  - Helena water supply (includes Charles T. Main reports, opinion in J.V. Weber vs. City of Helena, proceedings of Helena City Council), 1929-1943 (Box-folder 5 / 16)
  - Henderson Gulch Placer Mines, Granite County (correspondents include J.M. Thomas, W.S. Dawson), 1940 (Box-folder 5 / 17)
  - Hilger Placer Mine (J.G. Hilger, John M. Thomas), 1932, 1942 (Box-folder 5 / 18)
  - Home Mining and Milling Company, Marysville (re Towsley Gulch claims, Hardgrove-Williamson lease; correspondents include Hugh P. Evans, Dave Evans, F.P. Hixon; also includes report on company, 1888), 1888, 1937-1950 (Box-folder 5 / 19-21)
  - Homestake Mining Company, Lead, S.D. (Lawrence Wright, B.C. Yates), 1931 (Box-folder 5 / 22)
  - Hoover Dam (Compressed Air Magazine), 1930-1942 (Box-folder 5 / 23)
  - H, 1930-1950 (Box-folder 5 / 24)
  - Ideal Mining Company, Anaconda (re Conshohoken group of mines; correspondents include A.J. White), 1929 (Box-folder 5 / 25)
  - Intermountain Engineering-Development Company, Helena (correspondents include T.O. Hammond, E.B. Gibbs, E.E. Wager, Martin Woolston), 1929-1932 (Box-folder 5 / 26)
  - Iron Ore newspaper, Ishpeming, Michigan (re Ropes Mine, western mining politics), 1931-1950 (Box-folder 5 / 27)
  - Ishpeming Gold Mining Company, Ishpeming, Michigan (re Ropes Mine; correspondents include J.H. Trebilcock), 1932 (Box-folder 5 / 28)
  - I, 1931-1942 (Box-folder 5 / 29)
  - George R. Jackson (re family matters), 1942-1943 (Box-folder 5 / 30)
  - Josephine Gold Mining Company, Norris (A. Doornbos), 1936-1937, 1944 (Box-folder 5 / 31)
  - J, 1937 (Box-folder 5 / 32)
  - Khern Lode, Montana City (Louis A. Jaffer), 1933 (Box-folder 6 / 1)
  - H.G. Kleinschmidt property and Mike Horse Mine, Lincoln, 1929-1931, 1939 (Box-folder 6 / 2)
  - Korisek Mine, Canyon Ferry (William H. Sandstrom, Edgar H. Blair), 1939, 1948 (Box-folder 6 / 3)
  - K, 1929-1942 (Box-folder 6 / 4)
  - Alf M. Landon (re presidential election), 1936 (Box-folder 6 / 5)
  - Last Chance Gulch Mining Association, 1943-1950 (Box-folder 6 / 6)
  - Agnes Lewis (re pipeline on ranch on Warm Springs Creek, Jefferson County), 1933 (Box-folder 6 / 7)
  - L.A. and M.T. Leydig (re house in Lenox Addition, mining, etc.), 1932-1933 (Box-folder 6 / 8)
  - Little Ox and Big Ox mines, marysville (Lou W. Kreicker), 1932-1933 (Box-folder 6 / 9)
  - L, 1932-1942 (Box-folder 6 / 10)
  - MacDonald Pass, 1929 (Box-folder 6 / 11)
  - Mammoth Mine, Eagle Creek, Broadwater County (Charles Johnson, H.K. Bickford, A.V. Bergland), 1934 (Box-folder 6 / 12)
  - Mammoth Mines Corporation, Twin Bridges (Earl R. Pulver), 1936-1941 (Box-folder 6 / 13)
  - Manganese property, Jefferson City (William Delenais, Arthur and Henry Madison), 1942-1945 (Box-folder 6 / 14)
  - Marietta Mine, Townsend (correspondents include Al Dance, Herschel James, R.D. Mott and Company, Gold Butte Mining Company), 1936-1942 (Box-folder 6 / 15)
  - Mascotte Mine, Nevada Creek, Powell County (Harry F. Stone), 1930 (Box-folder 6 / 16)
  - McClelland Creek water, Elkhorn Mountains (James E. Keys, Peter Hilger), 1930 (Box-folder 6 / 17)
  - McKay Mine, Marysville (William J. Stratton), 1930 (Box-folder 6 / 18)
  - Michigan Collete of Mining and Technology (re alumni), 1931-1949 (Box-folder 6 / 19)
  - Mike Horse Mine, Lincoln (correspondents include Sterling Mining and Milling Company, E.E. Wager, Hunter Williams, Sam Stampfly, Tonopah Mining Company), 1924-1939 (Box-folder 6 / 20)
  - Frank J. Miller (re suit involving claims in Sheep Eater Mining District, Jardine; includes mining claim certificates, 1938-1941), 1944 (Box-folder 6 / 21)
  - Minah Mine, Wickes (correspondents include Henry M. Lancaster, Continental Gold Mines, Inc., Minah Consolidated Mines Corporation), 1930-1936, 1942 (Box-folder 6 / 22)
  - Mines Operating, Inc., Canyon Creek (re Home Mining and Milling Company, Earthquake and Skokapee mines; correspondents include Hugh P. Evans, F.P. Hixon), 1946 (Box-folder 6 / 23)
  - Mining Association of Montana (re meetings, St. Louis Mining and Milling Company), 1934 (Box-folder 6 / 24)
  - Mining equipment (correspondence with vendors: A-W; blueprints of ore crushing and reduction mill in OVERSIZE FOLDER), 1931-1937 (Box-folder 6 / 25-26)
  - blueprints of ore crushing and reduction mill [Oversize: See Archives Map Case], 1931-1937 (Oversize-folder 1)
  - Mining Truth, Spokane (re Rimini Mining District and Silver Camp, Lincoln), 1930 (Box-folder 6 / 27)
  - Monetary policy (re silver), 1933-1934, 1939 (Box-folder 6 / 28)
  - Montana-Chicago Mining Company, Mitchell Gulch, Jefferson County (re Last Hope, Starret, and Eureka mines; correspondents include Edmund G. toomey, Samuel Horwitz), 1936 (Box-folder 6 / 29)
  - Montana Geological Survey (re proposed bill), 1929 (Box-folder 6 / 30)
  - Montana Oil and Mining Journal (re Marysville mining properties), 1934-1939, 1943 (Box-folder 6 / 31)
  - Montana Power Company, 1932-1942 (Box-folder 6 / 32)
  - Montana-Silver Tip Mining Company, Wickes (re Silver Tip, Redding and Madison mines; correspondents include Henry Madison, R.A. Davidson, W.G. Swart, C.L. Holmberg, J.H. Pearce, George Redding), 1928-1930 (Box-folder 6 / 34)
  - Montana State Auditor, State Land Board, Industrial Accident Board, et al. (re mineral leasing, Capitol dome, Fort Peck, etc.), 1929-1934 (Box-folder 7 / 1)
  - Monte Christo Mine, Vipond Mining District (A.H. Johnson, James Sherman), 1945-1946 (Box-folder 7 / 2)
  - Mulgrew claims, Rimini (Anne Kirk Whitlock), 1951 (Box-folder 7 / 3)
  - M, 1929-1948 (Box-folder 7 / 4)
  - New Departure Mines, Inc., Dillon Harry Hickey, Wade V. Lewis), 1925-1949 (Box-folder 7 / 5)
  - New World Mining District, Cooke City, circa 1905 (Box-folder 7 / 6)
  - Nimrod lead mine, Missoula County (Frank O. Davis, Paul E. Flynn), 1941-1948 (Box-folder 7 / 7)
  - N, 1931-1946 (Box-folder 7 / 8)
  - Occidental Mining Company, Wickes (E.H. MacDonald, Harrison B. Martin), 1934-1935 (Box-folder 7 / 9)
  - Oil lease policy, 1929 (Box-folder 7 / 10)
  - Oker Mine, Flesher Pass (Joseph Oker, S.W. Wilson), 1929 (Box-folder 7 / 11)
  - O, 1931-1942 (Box-folder 7 / 12)
  - Pedro Mine, Helena (S.E. Howard), 1939 (Box-folder 7 / 13)